The Allen G. Tripp MD Papers
Archives and Special Collections at the SUNY Upstate Health Sciences Library
The Allen G. Tripp MD Papers
1896-1911
SUNY Upstate Medical University 766 Irving Avenue Syracuse, NY 13210
Tripp, Allen G.
.21 linear feet
This collection contains the papers of Allen G. Tripp, who graduated from the Syracuse University College of Medicine in 1900. The collection has two series, Writings and Memorabilia.
FIC2017.0001
Biographical Note
There are few details available for Allen Gideon Tripp (1868-1912). He was born in Clay, New York on November 13, 1868 and primarily lived in Cicero. He began his studies at the Syracuse University College of Medicine in 1896 and graduated in 1900. While at Syracuse University, he was the class president in 1898 and 1899 and was a member of the Iota Chapter of Alpha Kappa Kappa. He married Angie L. Overacre in June 1900 and died in 1912.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the papers of Allen G. Tripp, who graduated from the Syracuse University College of Medicine in 1900. There are two series in this collection.
Writings: this series contains Dr. Tripp’s notebooks, notes, and school materials from his academic career at Syracuse University College of Medicine.
Memorabilia: these documents include a diploma, membership certificate, and medical license.
Arrangement of the Collection
The Allen G. Tripp MD papers have been arranged into two series.
Subject and Genre Headings
Tripp, Allen G., 1868-1912; Alpha Kappa Kappa; Anatomy; Chemistry; Embryology; Histology; Medical education; Pathology; Phrenology; Physiology; Syracuse University, College of Medicine
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on this material.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Inventory
- Writings
  - Chemistry and physiology notebook and tipped in documents containing descriptions of chemistry laboratory experiments, reactions, dissections, equipment, anatomical sketches, and formulas and calculations, primarily with organic materials such as food (for example, “digestion of a beef sandwich” table) and body fluids. The back of the notebook contains many documents, such as notes on publications, patients, and remedies and enzymes; forms and notes on diagnosis of patients; the questions for written examination first year chemistry by Professor Smith and the schedule of the annual committee examinations and a course schedule at the Syracuse University College of Medicine; notes, tables, formulas and calculations, and anatomical drawings with information from class and laboratory experiments; a student ticket for the athletic association of Syracuse University; the menu for the installation dinner of the Iota Chapter of Alpha Kappa Kappa; the eulogy of Dr. Scott Owen by Nathan Jacobsen to the Onondaga County Medical Society; information and booklet on the laws and examination for license to practice medicine in New York; the menu, program, and autographs for the Iota Chapter of Alpha Kappa Kappa banquets of 1905 and 1911., 1896-1900 (Box Box 1)
  - 1897-1898 (Box Box 1)
  - Histology sketch book with sketches of cells and bacteria through the view of a microscope lens., 1896 (Box Box 1)
  - Class and patient notes with tables from class and forms and notes on diagnosis of patients., 1898 (Box Box 1)
  - Embryo sketchbook with sketches of embryos development, possibly from a frog., c. 1899 (Box Box 1)
  - Medicine notebook with notes from Professor Henry Leopold Elsner’s class and clinic on diseases, including remedies and descriptive observations., 1898-1899 (Box Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous notebook with notes, tables, and sketches on classes, patients, formulas, and Syracuse University's alma mater., c. 1899 (Box Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Certification of membership for The Onondaga Medical Society., 1904 (Box Oversize Case 8, Shelf 2)
  - Syracuse University College of Medicine diploma., 1900 (Box Oversize Case 8, Shelf 2)
  - License to practice medicine and surgery in the state of New York., 1900 (Box Oversize Case 8, Shelf 2)